hey everyone welcome to CS dojo my name
嘿大家欢迎来到CS dojo我的名字
is Mikey and I'm your host and today
是Mikey，我是你的主人，今天
we're going to talk about the top five
我们将讨论 前五名
programming languages to learn for
编程语言去 学习
getting a job at companies like Google
在 谷歌等 公司找到工作
Facebook Microsoft etc so the obvious
Facebook的微软 等方面的 明显
question here might be doesn't really
这里的问题 可能并不是真的
matter which languages you learn if
不管你学习哪种语言
you're trying to get a job at one of
你想在一个 找工作
these companies my answer would be yes
这些 公司我的答案是 肯定的
it does but not directly what I mean by
它确实但不 直接我的意思
that is when you have a job interview
也就是说当你有 一个面试
with one of these companies as a
与 这些公司 为 之一
software engineer candidate the most
软件工程师候选人最多
important thing they'll usually look for
他们通常会 寻找重要的事情
is not what specific language or
不是 什么特定的语言或
technology you've been using instead
你一直在使用的技术
they tend to look for mostly your coding
他们倾向于主要寻找你的编码
skills your problem-solving ability and
技能你 的解决问题的 能力和
your data structures and algorithms
你的数据结构和算法
knowledge so you might say wait why k so
所以你可能会说等待为什么 K 如此
it doesn't really matter which languages
哪种语言并不重要
I learned them my answer to that would
我学会了他们我的答案，那会
be actually it still matters a lot I'm
事实上，它仍然很 重要， 我是
going to explain my reasoning behind
去解释我的背后的推理
that in this video but if you just want
在这个视频中，但如果 你只是想
to find my lists just keep over to this
找到我的名单 只是继续 这一点
time in this video okay so if these
时间在这个视频好吧，如果这些
large companies don't care that much
大公司并不在乎
about which languages you know then why
你知道哪些语言为什么
does it matter at all which languages
这 对 所有的语言来说都很重要吗？
you learn if you want to get a job at
你知道你是否想找工作
one of these companies there are three
这些 企业 的 一个 有三个
reasons for this reason number one when
第一个原因是什么时候
you apply for a job at one of these big
你 在 这些大公司 申请 工作
companies how do you think they will
公司你觉得他们 会 如何
decide if they should invite you for a
决定他们是否应该邀请你 参加
job interview of course there are a few
当然面试的人有几个
different aspects to this for example
不同的方面，例如
your education your personal projects
你的教育你的个人项目
and so on but the biggest factor is
等等， 但 最大的因素 是
usually your work experience and how do
通常你的工作经验和做法
you get the experience in the first
你 在第一次 获得经验
place probably at smaller less known
可能位于较小的已知位置
companies first and actually smaller
公司第一，实际上更小
companies and startups tend to care more
公司和初创公司往往关心更多
about which specific language or
关于哪一种特定的语言或
technology you know so for example a
你知道的技术例如a
small start-up might say we need someone
小公司可能会说我们需要一个人
who can help us create an iOS app
谁可以帮助我们 创建一个iOS应用程序
tomorrow or we need someone who knows
明天还是需要知道的人
JavaScript really well by next month so
JavaScript的真的 很好下个月 如此
depending on which languages you know
取决于你知道哪种语言
it'll actually be easier or harder for
它实际上会更容易或更难
you to get a job at one of these smaller
你在 这些较小的 一个找到工作
companies and reason number two I think
公司和原因 排名 第二，我认为
you should learn a programming language
你应该学习一门编程 语言
that aligns with your interests so you
这符合你的兴趣，所以你
have more
有更多的
duration and reason for learning so for
持续时间 和原因 的学习 所以
example if you're interested in learning
例如，如果你有 兴趣学习
to make an iPhone app you should
制作iPhone 应用程序你 应该
probably learn Swift and if you're
可能学习Swift，如果你是
interested in data science machine
对数据科学机器感兴趣
learning or science in general
一般学习或科学
Python might be a good choice for you
Python 对你来说可能是一个不错的选择
reason number three some programming
原因三是一些编程
languages or simply easier to learn than
语言还是简单易学
some other ones for example I would say
例如我会说一些其他的
JavaScript is easier to learn than Java
JavaScript 比Java更容易学习
and Python is easier to learn than C++
Python 比C ++ 更容易 学习
so based on that I decided to use the
所以根据 我决定 使用
job market and ease of learning as the
就业市场和易于 学习 作为 的
two main criteria for making my list of
制定 我的清单的两个主要标准
top 5 programming languages to learn ok
排名前5的编程语言学习 OK
so here's my list number 5 Ruby Ruby is
所以这里是我的清单编号5 Ruby Ruby是
a programming language from Japan it
来自日本的编程语言
became popular due to the popularity of
因受欢迎而 流行起来
something called Ruby on Rails and Ruby
Ruby on Rails和Ruby
on Rails was at some point I would say
在Rails 上我会 说
the hardest framework for building
最难的建筑框架
websites although it's not as popular as
网站 虽然它不是那么 受欢迎
it used to be anymore
它曾经是 了
still a lot of companies use Ruby on
还有很多 公司使用 Ruby
Rails today and Ruby is a really simple
Rails今天和Ruby是一个非常简单的
and easy language to learn number four
和简单的语言学习 四号
swift Swift is now the primary language
Swift Swift现在是主要语言
for building an iOS app whether it's for
用于构建iOS 应用程序
iPhone or iPad if you have the skill it
iPhone或iPad，如果你有本事就
should be fairly easy for you to get a
应该对 你来说相当容易
job since many companies want to build
因为许多公司想要建立工作
iOS apps I haven't used this language
iOS应用程序我没有使用过这种语言
extensively myself but it seems like a
广泛我自己，但它似乎是一个
fairly simple and easy language to learn
相当 简单易学的语言
the only downside of Swift is that it's
Swift 唯一的缺点 就是它
not really cross-platform meaning it's
不是真正的跨平台的意思
not easy to create an iOS app with Swift
使用Swift创建iOS应用程序并不容易
if you don't have a Mac number three
如果你没有Mac三号
Java Java is probably one of the most
Java Java可能是其中之一
widely used programming languages today
当今广泛使用的编程语言
you can use Java to build many things
你可以 使用Java来构建很多东西
including Android apps many companies
包括许多公司的Android应用
use Java frameworks to create websites
使用Java框架 来 创建网站
as well unfortunately it's not the
不幸的是它不是
easiest language to learn since it's a
最简单的语言学习，因为它是一个
bit more complex than the other
比其他更复杂一点
languages in this list number two Python
这个列表中的语言编号为两个Python
Python is also a very popular
Python 也很受欢迎
programming language at least in North
编程语言至少在北方
America and many companies use it to
美国和许多公司使用它
create websites with frameworks like
用类似框架创建网站
Django and flask this is probably the
Django和烧瓶这可能是
language of your choice if you're
你选择的语言
interested in
有兴趣
things like data science machine
像数据科学机器一样
learning or science in general it's also
一般的学习或科学 也是如此
one of the main languages used at Google
Google使用的主要语言之一
so it's popular at both large companies
所以它在两家大公司都很受欢迎
and smaller companies and number one
和较小的公司和第一名
javascript javascript used to be a
JavaScript的JavaScript曾经是一个
language that only ran on your browser
只在您的浏览器上运行的语言
whether it's Chrome Firefox or Safari
无论是Chrome Firefox还是Safari
but recently people started using it to
但最近 人们开始使用 它
create back-end code meaning the code
创建代码的后端代码
that runs on your servers not just
不仅仅是在你的服务器上运行
front-end code meaning the code that
前端代码的含义就是代码
runs on your device whether it's a phone
在 设备 上运行， 无论是手机
or a laptop javascript is a great
或一台笔记本电脑的JavaScript是伟大的
language to learn for getting a job and
学习获得工作 和 学习的语言
it's also fairly simple and easy to
它也相当简单和容易
learn now if you're just getting started
现在学习，如果你是刚刚 开始
with programming I'd recommend that you
与 编程我会建议你
start with either Python or JavaScript
先从 Python或JavaScript的
and I think your optimal choice here
我认为 你的最佳选择在这里
mostly depends on your interests for
主要取决于 你的兴趣
example if you're interested in UI or
例如，如果你有 兴趣在用户界面或
user experience design then JavaScript
用户体验设计，然后是JavaScript
is probably the way to go if you're more
可能是如果你更要走 的路
into logic machine learning or science
进入逻辑机器学习或科学
in general python might be the right
一般python可能是 正确的
choice for you now I have three more
你的选择我现在有三个
languages for honorable mentions but I
语言为光荣的提及， 但我
have a quick announcement to make
有一个快速的发布的消息，
I've just launched my patreon page where
我刚刚启动了我的patreon页面
you can chip in a few dollars to join a
你可以在几块钱 中加入一块
private Facebook group and a private
私人Facebook组和私人
monthly live stream where you can ask me
每月直播， 你可以问我
any questions I'd much appreciate it if
我倒是有任何疑问感激如果
you can head over to CS dojo dot io / PT
你可以前往CS dojo dot io / PT
to support my channel so here's my
以支持我的频道， 所以这里是我的
honorable mention number one go which is
值得一提的是哪一个
also known as go lang this language was
也被称为 去郎这种语言 是
originally developed at Google but it's
最初是在谷歌开发的， 但它是
used extensively in many companies today
今天 在许多公司广泛使用
go is known for its efficiency and it's
去以其效率 和 它的
simple syntax and it's actually becoming
简单的语法，它实际上正在成为
one of the most popular programming
最流行的编程 之一
languages today so if you're looking to
今天的语言，所以如果你正在 寻找
add a language to your skill set this is
添加 语言到你的技能，这是
the first language I'd definitely
我肯定 是第一语言
consider honorable mention number two
考虑第二名
Courtland Courtland is a relatively new
考特兰考特兰是一个相对较 新的
language and it works in both a Java
语言和它的作品在上 使用 Java
based environment and a JavaScript based
基于JavaScript的环境和基于JavaScript的
environment Kotlin was recently
环境Kotlin最近
officially supported by Android so it's
Android正式支持， 所以它
possible that Colin will become the
科林可能会成为这样的人
primary language for developing Android
开发Android的主要语言
apps in the future honorable mention
应用程序在未来的荣誉提及
number three Seco with
第三名山高带
some people pronounce as SQL if you
如果你有人发音为SQL
search for what programming language to
搜索什么编程语言
learn you might run across on an article
学习 你可能会碰到一篇文章
or two that mention sequel but if you're
或两个提到续集，但 如果你是
beginner it might be confusing because
初学者可能会困惑，因为
Seco is different from all the other
山高与其他所有人不同
languages that we talked about in this
我们在此讨论的语言
video
视频
Seco or SQL is a programming language
山高或 SQL是一种编程语言
that solely focused on managing
只专注 于管理
databases it's usually used in
它通常用于的数据库
conjunction with one of the other
与另一个结合
languages so learning Seco as your first
语言让你像第一次学习山高
programming language is probably not the
编程语言可能不是
best idea and in my opinion it's not
最好的办法，在我看来 这不是
that easy to learn Seco without having
很容易学习山高没有
some real-life data to play with so I'd
一些真实的 数据，所以我会玩
focus on learning other languages first
首先重点学习其他语言
okay that's all I have for this video
好的，这就是我拥有 的这部影片
thanks as always for watching and again
感谢一如既往的收看和再次
I'd much appreciate it if you can head
如果你能领导，我将非常感激
over to my patreon page right here to
直到我的博客页面就在这里
support CS dojo and let me know in the
支持CS dojo并让我知道
comment below if you have any requests
如果您 有任何要求，请在下面评论
about what kind of videos I should make
我 应该制作 什么样的视频
in the future and I'll see you in the
将来，我会在你身边看到你
next video
下一个视频